<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tenzer.dk</title>
    <link>https://tenzer.dk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tenzer.dk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tenzer.dk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a server - The plan</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/making-a-server-the-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/making-a-server-the-plan/</guid>
      <description>I currently have a virtual server running at Hetzner, it&amp;rsquo;s used for hosting this website plus a few other projects of mine. I&amp;rsquo;ve been contemplating rebuilding it from scratch, and think it could be good to blog about and to give you some tips in case you feel inspired to do the same.
The current server has been ad-hoc configured over the years, I instead plan to make the new server a lot more structured and instead make use of configuration management for setting it up, a continuous integration server for checking and executing the configuration, &amp;ldquo;ChatOps&amp;rdquo; for day-to-day system administration and tools, metrics for the system and services, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing the icon of a Mac application</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/replacing-the-icon-of-a-mac-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/replacing-the-icon-of-a-mac-application/</guid>
      <description>I use a MacBook Pro for my daily computer needs. Not long after I got it, I installed smcFanControl in order to increase the idle fan speed, as the laptop otherwise got a bit too hot for my liking, even when doing non-CPU intensive tasks on the machine.
There is one problem with smcFanControl though, the menu bar entry for the program can either be the temperature and/or fan speed or just an icon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Subresource Integrity Checksums</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/generating-subresource-integrity-checksums/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/generating-subresource-integrity-checksums/</guid>
      <description>The GitHub Engineering blog recently had a blog post on how they have added Subresource Integrity (SRI) tags on their third party assets. Long story short, this is integrity attribute you add to your &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot;&amp;gt; tags which point to external (ie. not inlined) assets. Supporting browsers will then check the checksum in the attribute against the file it has downloaded before it parses the file. This is to make sure the file hasn&amp;rsquo;t been tampered with and to avoid the browser loading malicious files because some third party hoster got a security problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx with dynamic upstreams</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/nginx-with-dynamic-upstreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/nginx-with-dynamic-upstreams/</guid>
      <description>I recently made a setup at work where I had a Nginx server facing the user, which would forward requests to a service running behind an AWS Elastic Load Balancer (aka. ELB). That in itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like a difficult task, you just find the hostname for the ELB and point Nginx at it with a proxy_pass statement like this, right?
location / { proxy_pass http://service-1234567890.us-east-1.elb.amazonaws.com; } Test it out and - assuming the firewall/security group configuration is set up right - it should work just fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Output Format</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/python-output-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/python-output-format/</guid>
      <description>I use Sublime Text as my editor of choice, and I have loved how simple but effective the Pretty JSON plugin has been at making minimized JSON chunks into easy readable, neatly indented blocks of code with just one key press.
Since I mainly do my programming in Python I found that I for debugging often print out variables from Python code, in order to get an easier glimpse of what data I am working on or what I have produced thus far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide: Docker Registry Frontend</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/guide-docker-registry-frontend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/guide-docker-registry-frontend/</guid>
      <description>If you have your own private Docker registry you might be wanting some kind of frontend for it, as docker search [...] can only get you so far in regards to getting an overview of what the registry contains. Fortunately all the information you might want about the registry contents can be aquired through the REST API, making it possible to present the data neatly on a website.
Konrad Kleine has made the docker-registry-frontend project to do just that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide: Private Docker Registry</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/guide-private-docker-registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/guide-private-docker-registry/</guid>
      <description>I got to play around with Docker lately at work, and for that we needed a private place to store Docker images. Since the other guides I found either were unnecessarily advanced, or hosted the registry inside a Docker instance, instead of making use of our existing server setup, I&amp;rsquo;ve gone ahead and made a guide for how I set it up.
This guide shows the steps to take on an Ubuntu machine, but it should be easy to apply to other operating systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New website</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/new-website/</guid>
      <description>It has been in the making for some time but now it&amp;rsquo;s finally out. I&amp;rsquo;ve made a new design for my website and in the process also switched it from being based on Wordpress to now being a static site.
Back in July my colleague Esben started work on his own static site generator, Beetle, and I got interested in the project shortly after. Within a month I made the first pull request to Beetle while also acting as a sparring partner to Esben&amp;rsquo;s development work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Tweet Nest in Nginx</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/setting-up-tweet-nest-in-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/setting-up-tweet-nest-in-nginx/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;ve set up Tweet Nest at tweets.tenzer.dk. Tweet Nest is a simple application that archives all your tweets, and make it easy to search for old tweets you&amp;rsquo;ve written that you might want to find again. Tweet Nest comes by default with .htaccess files containing an Apache mod_rewrite specific configuration, but since I&amp;rsquo;m using Nginx that configuration won&amp;rsquo;t work for me.
The mod_rewrite rules are limited to rules for handling requests to /sort, /favorites, /search and pages to show tweets for a specific month and day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Football pictures and video</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/football-pictures-and-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/football-pictures-and-video/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I watched the Copenhagen Towers&amp;rsquo; (the American football team I play for) U19 team play the semi-finals in the national championships, and I did of course take pictures of it. They can all be found in the Flickr gallery for the game.
Tuesday this week Jens Rørbye - the media manager for Copenhagen Towers - contacted me and asked if I could help out with an interview of the teams American import quarterback player, JR Artozqui.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concert photography is fun!</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/concert-photography-is-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/concert-photography-is-fun/</guid>
      <description>In an attempt on getting a bit of activity back here on my blog, I thought I might as well update a bit on what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing lately.
A few weeks ago I went to the concert venue Gimle in Roskilde in order to watch some concerts, primarily with the Danish live drum and bass band F.U.K.T and electronic artist Rangleklods. I had listened to both artists a fair bit prior to the concert, and the concert was free so it was really a no brainer to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zenphoto Sitemap 2.0.0</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/zenphoto-sitemap-2.0.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/zenphoto-sitemap-2.0.0/</guid>
      <description>I have made a new version of the Zenphoto gallery plugin, Zenphoto Sitemap, available.
The new version is a rewrite of the plugin, in order to increase speed, decrease load and generally make the code easier to read, hence the version number. I have also included a README file in the package.
The new version can either be fetched from my project page, or from the new GitHub project page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing djbdns in an OpenSolaris zone</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/installing-djbdns-in-an-opensolaris-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/installing-djbdns-in-an-opensolaris-zone/</guid>
      <description>This guide shows you how to install djbdns in an OpenSolaris zone. The zone is currently running OpenSolaris build 124, but the guide should work on other versions of OpenSolaris as well, though not tested. The zone is simply set up as a default ipkg OpenSolaris zone, without many default installed packages.
First we start of with the installation of some packages, including sunstudio since we are going to use that to compile djbdns with:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating an OpenSolaris zone</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/updating-an-opensolaris-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/updating-an-opensolaris-zone/</guid>
      <description>This is just a quick guide for people who need to update an OpenSolaris zone. First off, you need to shutdown the zone. This can either by done by using init 5 or shutdown inside the zone, or by running any of the two commands with zlogin from the global zone. A final not recommended possibility is to run zoneadm -z &amp;lt;zonename&amp;gt; halt from the global zone.
After the zone is stopped, you will have to set the zone state to &amp;ldquo;ready&amp;rdquo;, in order for the file systems to be mounted:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts about package dependencies</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/some-thoughts-about-package-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/some-thoughts-about-package-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>Last night I installed SqueezeCenter (the server software used with Squeezebox&amp;rsquo;s) on my home server, since I want to use it together with SqueezeSlave running on my server. That way I can play music from my server while I have a webinterface to control it from all computers on my network.
For the installation of SqueezeCenter I downloaded the .deb package, since it was going to be installed on my home Ubuntu server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring the Solaris DHCP server</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/configuring-the-solaris-dhcp-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/configuring-the-solaris-dhcp-server/</guid>
      <description>As I recently had to configure the Solaris bundled DHCP server on a box, I though that I would write down the steps I took to get the task done, for everybody else to use and also for myself later on.
I will configure the server with some static entries for specific hosts, and also with a small pool of addresses for random users.
In order to get the DHCP server installed on OpenSolaris, you have to install the package named SUNWdhcs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zenphoto Sitemap 1.0.2</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/zenphoto-sitemap-1.0.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/zenphoto-sitemap-1.0.2/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a new version of my Zenphoto Sitemap available, which only includes one fix this time.
The change makes the plugin handle non-alphanumeric characters correctly, such as whitespaces, parentheses, brackets, international letters, etc. All those characters are now URL encoded when the sitemap is generated.
As always you can get the new version at the Zenphoto Sitemap page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zenphoto Sitemap 1.0.1</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/zenphoto-sitemap-1.0.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/zenphoto-sitemap-1.0.1/</guid>
      <description>I have updated my Zenphoto Sitemap plugin with two minor fixes.
The first change is that there won&amp;rsquo;t be specified any priorities in the sitemap at all, since the priorities only matter against other URLs in the same exact sitemap (ie. not site-wide). The plugin will have to be rewritten to have all URLs in the same sitemap in order to make use of priorities. As I haven&amp;rsquo;t experienced any need to specify the priority, it is simply left out and then the URLs are assigned the default priority (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zenphoto plugin: Zenphoto Sitemap</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/zenphoto-plugin-zenphoto-sitemap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/zenphoto-plugin-zenphoto-sitemap/</guid>
      <description>I have been coding a bit the last couple of days on a plugin for the gallery system Zenphoto. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very happy with how the images from my gallery where indexed, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any other decent coded sitemap generators for Zenphoto, so I decided to create one myself.
The result is a one-file plugin for Zenphoto, which is being activated by putting ?sitemap in the URL for your Zenphoto gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macro module for Apache</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/macro-module-for-apache/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/macro-module-for-apache/</guid>
      <description>This guide is about the wonderful mod_macro, which makes the job of managing an Apache webserver much easier, or just for the home developer with several test pages or projects.
I will explain how to get it running and give some examples of how I use the module, to help you get started with using it.
Installation First we need to get the module installed, since it is not installed in a default Debian/Ubuntu installation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>