<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tenzer.dk</title>
    <link>https://tenzer.dk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tenzer.dk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tenzer.dk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Replacing the icon of a Mac application</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/replacing-the-icon-of-a-mac-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/replacing-the-icon-of-a-mac-application/</guid>
      <description>I use a MacBook Pro for my daily computer needs. Not long after I got it, I installed smcFanControl in order to increase the idle fan speed, as the laptop otherwise got a bit too hot for my liking, even when doing non-CPU intensive tasks on the machine.
There is one problem with smcFanControl though, the menu bar entry for the program can either be the temperature and/or fan speed or just an icon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Subresource Integrity Checksums</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/generating-subresource-integrity-checksums/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/generating-subresource-integrity-checksums/</guid>
      <description>The GitHub Engineering blog recently had a blog post on how they have added Subresource Integrity (SRI) tags on their third party assets. Long story short, this is integrity attribute you add to your &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot;&amp;gt; tags which point to external (ie. not inlined) assets. Supporting browsers will then check the checksum in the attribute against the file it has downloaded before it parses the file. This is to make sure the file hasn&#39;t been tampered with and to avoid the browser loading malicious files because some third party hoster got a security problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx with dynamic upstreams</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/nginx-with-dynamic-upstreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/nginx-with-dynamic-upstreams/</guid>
      <description>I recently made a setup at work where I had a Nginx server facing the user, which would forward requests to a service running behind an AWS Elastic Load Balancer (aka. ELB). That in itself doesn&#39;t sound like a difficult task, you just find the hostname for the ELB and point Nginx at it with a proxy_pass statement like this, right?
location / {  proxy_pass http://service-1234567890.us-east-1.elb.amazonaws.com; } Test it out and - assuming the firewall/security group configuration is set up right - it should work just fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Output Format</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/python-output-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/python-output-format/</guid>
      <description>I use Sublime Text as my editor of choice, and I have loved how simple but effective the Pretty JSON plugin has been at making minimized JSON chunks into easy readable, neatly indented blocks of code with just one key press.
Since I mainly do my programming in Python I found that I for debugging often print out variables from Python code, in order to get an easier glimpse of what data I am working on or what I have produced thus far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide: Docker Registry Frontend</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/guide-docker-registry-frontend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/guide-docker-registry-frontend/</guid>
      <description>If you have your own private Docker registry you might be wanting some kind of frontend for it, as docker search [...] can only get you so far in regards to getting an overview of what the registry contains. Fortunately all the information you might want about the registry contents can be aquired through the REST API, making it possible to present the data neatly on a website.
Konrad Kleine has made the docker-registry-frontend project to do just that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide: Private Docker Registry</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/guide-private-docker-registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/guide-private-docker-registry/</guid>
      <description>I got to play around with Docker lately at work, and for that we needed a private place to store Docker images. Since the other guides I found either were unnecessarily advanced, or hosted the registry inside a Docker instance, instead of making use of our existing server setup, I&#39;ve gone ahead and made a guide for how I set it up.
This guide shows the steps to take on an Ubuntu machine, but it should be easy to apply to other operating systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New website</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/new-website/</guid>
      <description>It has been in the making for some time but now it&#39;s finally out. I&#39;ve made a new design for my website and in the process also switched it from being based on Wordpress to now being a static site.
Back in July my colleague Esben started work on his own static site generator, Beetle, and I got interested in the project shortly after. Within a month I made the first pull request to Beetle while also acting as a sparring partner to Esben&#39;s development work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts about package dependencies</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/some-thoughts-about-package-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/some-thoughts-about-package-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>Last night I installed SqueezeCenter (the server software used with Squeezebox&#39;s) on my home server, since I want to use it together with SqueezeSlave running on my server. That way I can play music from my server while I have a webinterface to control it from all computers on my network.
For the installation of SqueezeCenter I downloaded the .deb package, since it was going to be installed on my home Ubuntu server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zenphoto plugin: Zenphoto Sitemap</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/zenphoto-plugin-zenphoto-sitemap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/zenphoto-plugin-zenphoto-sitemap/</guid>
      <description>I have been coding a bit the last couple of days on a plugin for the gallery system Zenphoto. I wasn&#39;t very happy with how the images from my gallery where indexed, and I couldn&#39;t find any other decent coded sitemap generators for Zenphoto, so I decided to create one myself.
The result is a one-file plugin for Zenphoto, which is being activated by putting ?sitemap in the URL for your Zenphoto gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macro module for Apache</title>
      <link>https://tenzer.dk/macro-module-for-apache/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tenzer.dk/macro-module-for-apache/</guid>
      <description>This guide is about the wonderful mod_macro, which makes the job of managing an Apache webserver much easier, or just for the home developer with several test pages or projects.
I will explain how to get it running and give some examples of how I use the module, to help you get started with using it.
Installation First we need to get the module installed, since it is not installed in a default Debian/Ubuntu installation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
